Widget ManualMarch 11, 2017Abstract1
Page 2 of 15 CONTENTSContentsSummary ................................................................................... 11 Introduction ....................................................................... 12 Arrows ............................................................................... 23 IO ....................................................................................... 34 Action................................................................................. 65 Compute ............................................................................ 86 Logic................................................................................... 117 VAR .................................................................................... 138 Examples ............................................................................ 15 2
Page 1 of 15 1 INTRODUCTION1 IntroductionWidgets are divided into five kinds with different shapes:• IO• Action• Compute • Logic• VARTo connect widgets, two ways are offered.You can use: Define Arrows:• OUT for output or imply the sequence to execute the program • IN for input or imply the sequence to execute the program• UP arrows that locates at the top of widgets• DOWN arrows that locates at the bottom of widgets• LEFT arrows that locates at the left of widgets• RIGHT arrows that locates at the right of widgetsSymbols can be combined like OUT-DOWN, meaning this arrow locates at the bottom of the widget and acts as an output of data(or just tell you the next widgets to execute).Or:Contain several widgets in a Logic, meaning applying that logic to those widgets. 1
Page 2 of 15 2 ARROWS  In some situations, ”brick” is used to refer to widget.2 ArrowsThis is a small section describing how to use arrows. In the future, it may be expanded.Arrows can be joint or separated as following:2
Page3of15 3 IO  Amounts are not limited.While several arrows are joint, it means the next widget to execute of both ways is the same one.While an arrow is separated into several arrows, it means:• The value/variable is conveyed to several widgets• The next widgets to execute are more than one. It’s shall be informed that this way is how we realize parallel performing.At least one of the functions above works.3 IOAn IO consists of three parts:• Identity region. To identify what’s it(not realized yet).• Variable region. To define a variable or designate a certain variable. Also be used to output the variables. See in eg1.eps. More functions may be realized later.3
Page4of15 3 IO • Acceptance region. To accept the parameters needed for an IO to work.An IO can only have a limited amount of variables. If more are defined, former ones will be deleted. Them can be output individually.Variables need definition only once. If it is contained in a Logic like while, though the body is executed more than once, the variable is defined only at the first time when the IO is detected.IO bricks should have at least one arrow(RIGHT-OUT arrow). Those RIGHT- OUT arrows are used for data transmission and cannot be other kinds. The UPs or DOWNs just imply execution sequence. 4
Page5of153 IO  5
Page 6 of 15 4 ACTION4 ActionAn Action consists of three parts:• Action region. To store various commands.• Selection region. To choose from some options or type in certain value. • Acceptance region. To accept the parameters to take the action.Actions should have IN arrows, OUT arrows or both. UP and DOWN ar- rows are used to connect two Action bricks. Actions are executed in series.Here is an envisagement for future:IO bricks are permitted to connect to Action bricks in some situations. That happens when the vehicle needs a parameter to act and that action cannot be breakdown into more detailed widgets. In that case, LEFT or RIGHT arrows are placed and IOs shall be executed before an Action. 6
Page 7 of 154 ACTION  7
Page 8 of 15 5 COMPUTE5 ComputeA Compute consists of three parts:• IN region. To accept the data comes from IO,VAR or Compute. Only oneport.• OUT region. To output the result of calculation. Only one port. • Calculation region. Imply what this widget can do.Only support several modes of operation, considering that middle school students use little advanced expression.Each Compute has only one compute sign.Must have IN arrow. Some have a port for constant, where you can type in your own value. 8
Page 9 of 155 COMPUTE  9
Page 10 of 155 COMPUTE  10
Page 11 of 15 6 LOGIC6 LogicA Logic consists of two parts:• Factor region. To store logical judgement. • Implementation region. To contain bricks.Bricks to be executed should be placed inside the Logic and all kinds of widgets can be contained. It’s worth noting that Logic can also be nested in another Logic.Logic shouldn’t have OUT arrows. But they may have an IN arrow for their factors(point to factor region). Some special Logic are exclusive and commented additionally.To communicate between two Logics(not nested), use arrows to connect bricks or factor regions in those Logics. 11
Page 12 of 156 LOGIC  12
Page 13 of 15 7 VAR7 VARA VAR consists of two parts:• Type region. To designate the type. If a constant is wanted, it should alsobe type in it like ”num 5”.• Variable region. To define at most 6 variables. Initialization can be done here, like ”a=5”.Only variable region has arrows(IN and OUT). Each type of arrows are al- lowed only one. To output to more widgets, refer to Introduction.IN arrows convey the value to certain variable to initiate it. OUT arrows coney the variable to other bricks.If one unit is used, it means get that variable, as explained below. It’s worth noting that OUT conveys the variable not only the value! 13
Page 14 of 157 VAR  14
Page 15 of 158 ExamplesOnly one provided yet.8 EXAMPLES  15